Bruno Carballo

bruno@godinenbicicleta.com Mexico City, Mexico

Profile

Data Scientist at Descifra, with experience handling spatial databases using PostGIS and Python and focusing on automating data analysis workflows. Solid background in Mathematics and analytical thinking. Exceptional problem-solving skills. Passionate about python and data analysis.

Experience

DATA SCIENTIST, DESCIFRA, MARCH 2018 - PRESENT

- Spatial data analysis
- Develop new data pipelines to make analysis more efficient.
- Build new automated solutions for our clients

Accomplishments:

- Combine AWS Lambda functions, EC2, S3, Athena, PostgreSQL, PostGIS and Python to build a data pipeline from scratch that processes daily location data from more than 2 million devices. The outputs are custom indicators that help our clients make both marketing and expansion decisions.
- Teach our team of analysts to do web scraping using Python to get the competitor's locations for our clients.
- Build automated reports using Python, matplotlib, pandas, psycopg2, PostgreSQL, HTML and CSS.

RETAIL ACCOUNT EXECUTIVE, NIELSEN, JUNE 2017 - MARCH 2018

Part of the team working for Walmart, Nielsen's largest retailer account in Mexico

DATA ANALYST, NIELSEN, NOV 2016 - JUNE 2017

Data analysis (sales, prices, distribution, etc) for both retailers and CPGs.

Education

Universidad Nacional Autonoma de México, Bachelor of Science (B.S) in Physics 2009-2014

Software

Python (pandas, numpy, matplotlib, psycopg2, basic flask and django), PostGIS, PostgreSQL, Qgis, basic javascript, basic HTML, basic CSS, basic d3.js